<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>Installation</title>
  </header>
  <body>

    <section id="prerequests">
      <title>Prerequests</title>
      <table>
        <tr>
          <th>Component</th>
          <th>Version</th>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Apache HTTPD (+ mod_rewrite for REST-Interface)</td>
          <td>all should work</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>PHP as Apache module</td>
          <td>4.3.x/4.4.x/5.x</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>MySQL or PostgreSQL</td>
          <td>4.x/5.x(My) or 7.x/8.x(Postgre)</td>
        </tr>
      </table>
    </section>

    <section id="freshinstall">
      <title>Fresh Installation</title>
      <p>
        For a new, fresh installation we need to download a 7z-/Zip-archive of Schoorbs. To make 
        Schoorbs accessible from the web we need to extract the archive into a directory, which the
        webserver can access. In the most common cases on Linux, you use /var/www.<br />
        <code>$ cd /var/www</code><br />
        <code>$ 7zr x schoorbs.7z</code>
        or
        <code>$ unzip schoorbs.zip</code><br /><br />
        After we have extract all the files, we need to copy config.inc.php-dist to config.inc.php
        we will later set all configuration options. <br />
        <code>$ cd schoorbs</code><br />
        <code>$ cp config.inc.php-dist config.inc.php</code><br /><br />
        Now all files need for Schoorbs are in the right place and should be accessbile by the 
        wevserver, for the storage of the data of the bookings and available rooms, we need to
        setup the database.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section id="database">
      <title>Database setup</title>
      <p>
        If you're making a new installation of Schoorbs, you have to generate the database 
        environment for it. There are some differences between MySQL and PostgreSQL which are
        explained in the following paragraphs.
      </p>
      <section id="database-mysql">
        <title>MySQL</title>
        <p>
          First, we connect to the database as root, if you have set a password for root, you need to
          the option --password at the end of this command.<br />  
          <code>$ mysql --user=root mysql</code><br /><br />

          If you do not already have a database were we could create the tables for schoorbs, then we
          need to create one, we name it schoorbs in this example.<br />
          <code>mysql&gt; CREATE DATABASE schoorbs;</code><br /><br />

          For access to the database we need a valid combination of username and password, in the best 
          (most secure) case, it just has access to the database in which we store the data for 
          Schoorbs. If already one exists, skip this step.<br />
          <code>mysql&gt; GRANT ALL PRIVILEGES ON schoorbs.* TO 'schoorbs'@'%' IDENTIFIED BY 'test';</code> 
          generates a user schoorbs with password test and full access to the database schoorbs.<br /><br /> 
        
          In the next step we need to create the tables. With the given file 
          <a href="tables.my.sql">tables.my.sql</a> you create all the needed tables with the prefix
          'schoorbs_', if you want another prefix, you have to change it at each command. For legacy/
          backward-compability-cases, it's a <a href="tables-legacy.my.sql">tables-legacy.my.sql</a>
          available, where all commands start with 'mrbs_'. The following command should execute the 
          sql-commands from the file in the file: <br />
          <code>$ mysql schoorbs &lt; --user=schoorbs --password=test tables.my.sql</code>
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="database-postgresql">
        <title>PostgreSQL</title>
        <p>
          If we need to create a database for the PostgreSQL-setup, we could do this with a command,
          that is slightly shorter than the MySQL one:
        </p>
        <p>
          <code>$ createdb schoorbs</code>
        </p>
        <p>
          In opposite to MySQL where we have one SQL-file for all versions, with PostgreSQL, we have 
          to seperate between the server-versions before 7.3 and 7.3+. For the old school database 
          users we have <a href="tables.pg.sql">tables.pg.sql</a> with 'schoorbs_' as the command 
          prefix, for legacy cases there is a <a href="tables-legacy.pg.sql">tables-legacy.pg.sql</a>
          with 'mrbs_'-prefix available too. The modern 7.3+ users should use 
          <a href="tables.pg.73and_above.sql">tables.pg.73and_above.sql</a>('schoorbs_')
          or <a href="tables-legacy.pg.73and_above.sql">tables-legacy.pg.73and_above.sql</a>
          ('mrbs_'), because there are some differences in the SQL-syntax between those generations.
          You can apply those SQL-commands to your database with
        </p>
        <p>
          <code>$ psql -a -f tables.pg.sql schoorbs</code>
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="database-schoorbs-config">
        <title>Databaseconfiguration in Schoorbs</title> 
        <p>
          After we now should have a working database structure, we need to tell Schoorbs how to access
          the database. All configuration about database in done in Schoorbs at the head of the 
          config.inc.php. At first we have to inform Schoorbs which database driver it should use
          (variable <code>$dbsys</code>), for PostgreSQL we have at the moment only one option, the 'psql'-driver.
          But if you use MySQL, you can choose, if you want to use the 'mysql'- oder the 
          'mysql<strong>i</strong>'-driver. You can use the 'mysql'-driver for PHP 4 and PHP 5,
          but the 'mysqli'-driver is limited to PHP 5. It does not really make a difference which
          driver you use, 'mysql' may be more stable and 'mysqli' may have a better performance.
        </p>
        <p>
          With <code>$db_host</code> we tell Schoorbs where the database server is running, in most cases
          'localhost' is the best choice. In <code>$db_database</code> we set the database where the tables
          are stored, the table prefix is defined in <code>$db_tbl_prefix</code>. <code>$db_login</code>
          and <code>$db_password</code> are the places to store the authentication details. If you want to
          use peristent (pooled) connection, you have to set <code>$db_nopersist</code> to true.
        </p>
      </section> 
    </section>

    <section id="calendar-setup">
      <title>Calendar settings</title>
      <p>
        In Schoorbs there are two ways to setup the calendar, the first one is the clock-based. It lets you
        define when the days starts and when it ends. In this timespan, it is always possible to book the 
        room/resource but only in fixed timespan, e.g. all 45 minutes. The other way is the period-based.
        Here you define timespans by giving them a name rather than setting up a fixed time unit, these
        names could be times too, but they all will be handled as strings. You choose your favourite system
        by setting <code>$enable_periods</code> either to true or to false.  
      </p>

      <section id="period-calendar">
        <title>Setting up a period-based calendar</title>
        <p>
           Creating a period-based calendar is very simple. You just define in the configurationfile how
           your timespand are named and add them to the the <code>$period</code>-array. E.g.:
        </p>
        <p>
          <code>$periods[] = "08:00-08:45";</code>
        </p>
      </section>

      <section id="clock-calendar">
        <title>Setting up a clock-based calendar</title>
        <p>
          A clock-based calendar may not be as simple as a period-based calendar, but it could save 
          you the work of naming each time unit. At first we have to define in <code>$resolution</code>
          how long a timespan is, the length is defined in seconds, so a time unit of half an hour 
          would be <code>$resolution = 1800;</code>. With <code>$morningstarts</code> you set the 
          hour when a day starts, with <code>$morningstarts_minutes</code> you do it with the minutes.
          <code>$eveningends</code> and <code>$eveningends_minutes</code> do the same for the end of 
          the day. For people who care about the beginning of the week, could set this with 
          <code>$weekstarts</code> either to sunday(set to 0) or monday(set to 1). In some countries
          it is common to have the da in front of the month, in others there's the month in front of 
          the day. Schoorbs takes care of this difference with <code>$dateformat</code>, with a value
          of '0' the month is in front, with 1 it's the day. Another difference is the hour format, 
          mostly english contries have 1-12pm/am, the others have 0-23/24, for the first case you
          have to set <code>$twentyfourhour_format</code> to 0, for the other case to 1.   
        </p>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section id="auth">
      <title>Authentication</title>
      <p>
        For installation instructions concerning authentication, please read the special page about
        it.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section id="misc-setup">
      <title>Miscellaneous settings</title>
      <p>
        Excluding the site identification settings there are a lot more simple settings. In the 
        configuration file, they are all metioned by small comment each.<br />
        These settings control:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          the maximum number of repeat entries which can be created at once (a safety feature)
        </li>
        <li>
          the default report time period
        </li>
        <li>
          the number of search results to return per page
        </li>
        <li>
         the page refresh rate
        </li>
        <li>
          the way area/rooms are selected (html list or a drop-down select box)
        </li>
        <li>
          the way entries are displayed in monthly view (start/end slot, brief description or both)
        </li>
        <li>
          the way weeks are displayed in the bottom of the page (as week numbers (ie.
          42) instead of 'first day of the week' (13 Oct))
        </li>
        <li>
          display of times on right and left side in day and week view
        </li>
        <li>
          display of horizontal stripes on the day view
        </li>
        <li>
          cells highlighting options
        </li>
        <li>
          the default starting view (month, week or day)
        </li>
        <li>
          the default room to start with
        </li>
      </ul>
      <section id="site-id-setup">
        <title>Site identification information</title>
        <p>
          With the variables <code>$mrbs_admin</code> and <code>$mrbs_admin_email</code> you define who your 
          administration contact is and under which mail he is contactable. This information is shown on the
          help-page. If you want to change the branding in the left top, you have to edit <code>$mrbs_company</code>.
          Please take special care of this variable, because the content of it is send directly to the user, which
          makes it possible to insert (X)HTML-Code in it. When Schoorbs is running behind a proxy, it sometimes
          may happen that the URLs are broken, to override the used URL-base you just need to set <code>$url_base</code>
          to a valid adress. 
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="mail">
        <title>E-Mail support</title>
        <p>
          At the moment mail support is not considered as stable since we had to switch to a other 
          mail-protocol-wrapper library through legal issues.  For experimental/hopeful users, please
          refer to our copy of the old MRBS documentation (the mail-wrapper is still backwards compatible). 
        </p>
      </section>
    </section>
    <p>
      <a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">
        <img alt="Creative Commons License" style="border-width:0" src="http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/3.0/80x15.png" />
      </a>
    </p>

  </body>
</document>
