<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>Enduser documentation for Schoorbs</title>
  </header>
  <body>
    <section id="download">
      <title>Where to download</title>
      <p>
        You will find always the newest version of Schoorbs on our 
        <a href="http://schoorbs.xhochy.com/releases.html">Releases</a> page.
        If you want to use Schoorbs for productive environments, you should 
        choose the latest available <strong>stable</strong> version. If you 
        are interested in new/upcoming features in Schoorbs, but do not want to
        use this installation for every-day-usage, you might want to check out
        the latest unstable version. Please consider unstable version are likely
        more buggy because they are untested, stable version have already been
        tested a longer period, so that most bugs have already been fixed for them.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section id="help">
      <title>Where to get help with problems</title>
      <p>
        If you get problems with Schoorbs (maybe while installing), it is the best to sent a mail to 
        <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/schoorbs-general-discussion">the Schoorbs mailinglist</a>.
      </p>
      <p>
        If your problem is (or could be) a bug in Schoorbs, you should report it at our 
        <a href="http://code.google.com/p/schoorbs/issues/list">Issuse Tracker @ Google Code</a>
        <strong>too</strong>.
      </p>
    </section>

    <section id="license">
      <title>License</title>
      <p>
        While Schoorbs is licensed under the GPLv2, the end-user documentation is licensed under the 
        "Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported"-license, which is not a strict 
        copyleft license, but is more permissive than the GPLv2 and it isn't a license that was made
        for software cases only. All documentation included in the code of Schoorbs such as the
        API-docs are licensed under the GPLv2. Some parts of the documentation maybe stripped out of
        the INSTALL, README ... files of MRBS the pages containing those texts do not have a 
        CC-BY-SA-logo at the button and are licensed under the GPLv2. We want to replace all of the
        GPLv2-documentation because a single license for the whole end-user documentation is more 
        user-friendly and the old MRBS documentation could be already outdated, we just keep it, 
        to not have undocumented parts of software.
      </p>
    </section>

    <p>
      <a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">
        <img alt="Creative Commons License" style="border-width:0" src="http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/3.0/80x15.png" />
      </a>
    </p>

  </body>
</document>
