<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V2.0//EN" "http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/document-v20.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>Common usage</title>
  </header>
  <body>
    <section id="booking">
      <title>Booking a  ressource</title>
      <p>
	By default you start a booking process by clicking on a green cross in
	the timetable. It doesn't matter which room or time you click on, it's
	only important that you click in the right <strong>area</strong> on a cross, all other
	parameters could be changed on the following page.
      </p>
      <figure alt="Tabelle zur Raumbuchung" src="images/enduser-doku1.jpg" />
      <p>
        After you clicked on a cross, you will be redirect to the page "Add Entry".
        In brief description you should give a short title for this booking, a
        full description is optional but provides all other users a more detailed
        information what this booking is about. If you are using periods in your
        Schoorbs installation, you only have to choose the start periods and how
        long it will last, users with time-based calendars choose the start time, 
        the duration and the unit of the duration, e.g. hours.
      </p>
      <figure alt="Tabelle zur Raumbuchung" src="images/enduser-doku3.jpg" />
      <p>
      	Everything explained until yet is important for all types of entries, 
      	single or repeated ones. If you want to add a reoccuring/repeated entry
      	the last lines of this form are interesting for you. The "Repeat End Date"
      	specifies the day of the last entry of this repeated booking. Above this
      	field you could choose the type of the repeating, for n-weekly, you could
      	choose below the dayes when the entry is repeated. After a click on "Save"
      	either the day view with the new entry added or a list of conflicting 
      	bookings will be shown.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section id="change">
      <title>Changing a booking</title>
      <p>
        Is a booking not anymore required, than you could delete is as long as
        its start time isn't already in the past. By clicking on the entry in 
        the timetable you will be redirected to a page with information about 
        this entry. At the bottom of this page there is a link "Delete Entry".
        Using this link you will only delete the current entry, if you want to 
        delete a whole series, you could click on "Delete series", but remember
        that this action could not be done in reverse, so please think carefully
        about what you are doing.
      </p>
      <p>
        If you have made a mistake during the creation of the enty, you do not 
        need to delete the entry and create a new one (like in some other 
        software). On the page with the detailed information about an entry you 
        could click on "Edit entry" and change everything exactly like when you
        are creating a new entry. If you want to edit a whole series, you should 
        use "Edit series".
      </p>
    </section>
    <p>
      <a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">
        <img alt="Creative Commons License" style="border-width:0" src="http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/3.0/80x15.png" />
      </a>
    </p>
  </body>
</document>
